Joy Division "Love Will Tear Us Apart"
* when the routine bites hard *
* and ambitions are low *
* and resentment rides high *
* but emotions won't grow *
* and we're changing our ways *
* taking different roads *
* love will tear us apart again *
最棒一次演出了 Dante! 偉大的演出!
Best show ever, dante! Great show!
幹得好! 漂亮極了! 讓我....
Nice job! Beautiful.Just let me…
聽著 你不能去媄 知道嗎? 待在那
Hey,uh,look,you're not allowed to be over there, all right? Stay there.
他來了
Here he comes.
我知道 我知道 我知道
I know. I know. I know.
他盯著我看呢 你看到了嗎?
He looked right at me. Did you see that?
我看到了 我看見他盯著你看
I saw it. I saw him look right at you.
我倆之間有火花誒
We had a connection.
他唱的時候 好像劇院堜狾酗H都消失了
When he sang "resurrection" it was like everyone in the theater just disappeared.
他唱得如此漂亮 太棒了 真絕了 夥計
He is so beautiful. So beautiful. Totally,man.
太漂亮了 我們走了
So beautiful. This is us.
兩個都走? 是的
Both of you? Yeah.
我們住在同一街區 白癡
We live on the same block,dummy.
可以...陪你們走回去 什麼?
I could,uh,walk you to your building. What?
天...天黑了嘛 然後呢?
I mean,it's…it's dark. So?
我們得走了 我只是說天黑了 我可以陪你們走...
We gotta go. I'm just saying,it's dark.I could walk you…
我肯定比你更強壯 Ted
I'm pretty sure I'm tougher than you are,ted.
多謝你帶我們來看演唱會 Ted 再見!
Thank you for taking us to the concert,though,ted. Yeah. Bye!
再見 我叫Ed 不是Ted
Byebye. It's ed,not ted.
最近一名受害者叫Tara Farris 20歲
The latest victim is tara farris,20.
她是兩周內的第3名受害者
She's the third victim in 2 weeks.
都是上下班的人在公路出口發現的
All found on freeway offramps by commuters.
他沒有把屍體藏起來
Well,he's not hiding them.
扔在洛杉磯早高峰的公路上 他想讓人們發現屍體
An l.a.freeway during morning rush hour? He wants them found.
越快發現越好
Quickly.
她們還穿著衣服 基本不會嚇到路人
Well,they're still dressed. That minimizes the shock value.
也許他關心她們 希望她們能得到照顧?
Maybe he's concerned for them. Think he wants them taken care of?
受害者都沒遭受性侵犯
No signs of sexual assault on any of the victims.
看她臉色多蒼白
Look how pale she is.
她們都有嚴重脫血
All of them were severely hypovolemic.
Tara體內剩下不到1品脫的血
Tara had less than a pint of blood in her.
看這個 前兩個受害者 都剩下3品脫多的血
Look at this. The first 2 had more than 3 pints each.
如果他的目標是放血 不明嫌犯顯然已經駕輕就熟
If exsanguination is the goal, the unsub is definitely becoming more proficient.
這一點是新的 Tara是唯一留下信息的受害者
This is new. Tara's the only victim to have a written message.
"你這騙子"
"the liar."
"你這"騙子 很怪對吧?
"the" liar. That's strange,isn't it?
不是"一個騙子"或僅僅"騙子"
Not a liar or just liar.
你到底撒什麼謊了 Tara?
So what did you lie about,tara?
所有受害者都被勒死 然後放血
All of the victims appear to have been strangled and then bled out
喉嚨上有一樣的傷口
through identical wounds in the throat.
等等 說真的 這印子是尖牙咬的嗎?
Wait…seriously, are those supposed to be fang marks?
受害者身上所有傷口都留有唾液
All of the wounds on the victims were covered in saliva.
人類唾液 好像是... 有人喝了她們的血
Human saliva, as though… Someone drank their blood.
犯罪心理 第五季 第7集
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode07 The Performer
在所有描述邪惡鬼怪的黑暗文字
In all the darkest pages of the malign supernatural,
沒有比描述吸血鬼傳統更可怕的了
There is no more terrible tradition than that of the vampire.
他是魔界的賤民
A pariah even among demons.
作家 Montague Summers
Writer montague summers.
好的 謝謝 他們已經在洛杉磯 安排了特遣部隊
Ok,thanks. So they've already set up a task force in los angeles.
這不是他們第一宗連環殺人案
This isn't their first serial case.
還記得Owen Kim探員嗎? 上次查跟蹤案的
You remember detective owen kim? From the stalker case.
你還記得那宗案子 對吧 Spence?
You remember that case, don't you,spence?
我是記得那案子
I do remember that case.
還有沒有... 跟那個Lila聯繫了?
Yeah,you ever talk to,um, lila anymore?
我想我們現在應該 把注意力集中在這個案子上
You know,i think we should probably focus on this case right now.
這樣做比較合適
It's a little more pertinent.
好 說說吸血的傢伙吧 Reid
All right,so tell us about blooddrinkers,reid.
嗜人血者 或者叫臨床吸人膏血者 被稱作Renfield綜合癥
Human blood consumption, or clinical vampirism, is known as renfield's syndrome,
是根據布拉姆·斯托克的小說中 一個吃昆蟲的角色而命名的
Named after the insecteating character in bram stoker's novel "dracula."
他們是虐待狂嗎? 不一定
Are they sadists? Not necessarily.
給受害者帶來的傷害通常是順帶的 他們關注的是人血
Pain to the victim is usually only a byproduct. Blood is the focus.
Renfield綜合癥通常伴有 不同程度的精神分裂癥
Renfield's syndrome is usually accompanied by varying levels of schizophrenia
如果發展得更厲害 更會有典型的同類相食
And occasionally more classic cannibalism if the condition evolves.
典型的同類相食 咱這工作真是開眼界呀
Classic cannibalism. Lovely job we have.
這麼說吧…真實的案件極少
I will say this… true cases are exceedingly rare.
總算讓人舒了口氣 算是吧
That's comforting. Sort of.
Renfield癥患者可能罕見 吸血鬼卻到處都是
Renfield's may be rare, but vampires are anything but.
洛杉磯有非常龐大的 "吸血不死"亞文化群
And there's a huge subculture in los angeles of the reddrinking undead.
我怎麼見怪不怪呢
Why is that not a surprise?
Garcia 這些人都吸血嗎?
Garcia,all these people drink blood?
正相反 大部分只是像Prentiss高中時那樣 搞一身裝扮 然後裝神弄鬼
Au contraire. They mostly just dress up like prentiss did in high school and they make believe.
品味各不相同呀 這兩個根本是天壤之別
It's all kinds of delicious. It's not the same thing at all.
事實上 我們該說不明嫌犯是個 吸血鬼主義者 而不是吸血鬼
As a matter of fact, we should refer to this unsub as a vampirist,not a vampire.
他們被亞文化吸引 僅僅是因為它對人血的崇拜
And they would be attracted to the subculture merely for its professed worship of blood.
好吧 我繼續在各種網站挖掘
Ok,i'm going to continue spelunking through the various online sites,
看有沒啥東西跳出來 咬我一口
See if anything jumps up and bites me.
謝謝 寶貝... 謝謝 Penelope 跟緊點
Thanks,baby g… Thanks,penelope. Stay close.
遵命 長官  Garcia斷線
Yes,sir. Garcia out.
各位 還有一點 吸血鬼主義者貪得無厭
You guys,one more thing… vampirists are coveters.
一般都是和受害者有某種聯繫
They most generally always have some sort of relationship with the victim,
就算只是一面之緣 也會讓他們如癡如醉
Even if it's tangential. And they're likely to become obsessed.
他們肯定在某方面有交集
They've almost certainly crossed paths in some way.
加利福尼亞州 洛杉磯
沒事的 只有我 是Ray 你咋還在睡呢?
It's ok. It's just me. It's ray. You still in bed?
我病了
I'm sick.
聽著 Dante 你已經遲到了
Look,dante, you're already late.
別這麼叫我 對不起 夥計 你得出發了 好嗎?
Don't call me that. Sorry,but,man, you gotta get going,ok?
我說不去
I said no.
唱片公司又要發火了 如果你不…
The record company is gonna be pissed again.If you're not…
出去!
get out!
我知道你討厭這些聚會 但是你要把唱片賣出去呀
I know you hate these parties, but you've got to sell the record.
你不能撒手不管 這是你的工作 夥計
You can't blow this off. It's your job,man.
我的工作則是催你
And it's my job to make you go.
必須變成他嗎?
Do I have to be him?
你知道你必須的
You know that you do.
我20分鐘後準備好 很好 我給你準備點吃的
I'll be down in 20 minutes. Great. I'll make you something to eat.
我不餓
I'm not hungry.
昨晚怎麼了? 什麼意思?
What happened to you last night? What do you mean?
演出結束後 你好像人間蒸發了
After the show. You just kind of disappeared.
我不記得了
I don't remember.
嗨 Kim副隊長 我是Jareau探員
Hi,lieutenant kim. Agent jareau.
JJ嘛 我知道 我記得你們大部分人
Jj,of course. I remember most of you.
Hotchner探員 Reid Morgan
Agent hotchner. Reid. Morgan.
歡迎回到西海岸
Welcome back to the left coast.
這兩位是Prentiss和Rossi探員 相信你沒見過他們
These are agents prentiss and rossi. I believe they're new to you.
很高興認識你
Pleasure.
我們已經整理出一房間 擺好玻璃板 案卷 以及超難喝的咖啡
We already have a room set up full of glass boards, case files, and extremely bad coffee.
更艱難的我們都合作過
We've worked with a lot less.
現在Morgan探員是老大 他說了算
Agent morgan's in charge now. It's his show.
說來話長
Long story.
我知道你們喜歡從最新線索入手 然後往回分析
I know you like to start with the freshest information and work your way back.
Tara的公寓已經處理過並封鎖起來 留著讓你們去
So tara's apartment has been processed and sealed in case you want to go there.
她的屍體 和前2個遇害的女生一起
And her body,along with that of the first 2 girls,
都在停屍房 驗屍員隨時等候
Is at the morgue with an m.e.waiting there for your call.
好吧 JJ 把這埵洵B妥當 和Garcia聯繫上
All right. Jj,get set up here, and then hook up with garcia.
把目擊證人的信息傳給她 讓她同前2個遇害者的資料交叉比對
Send her the witness information so she can start crossreferencing with the first 2 victims.
Reid 我要你閱讀所有的案卷資料
Reid,i want you to go through all the case files,
根據你對精神病理學的研究 寫一份初步側寫
Set up a preliminary profile based on what you already know about the psychopathology.
其他人 我們去看看 從Tara身上能找到什麼
And the rest of us,let's find out what we can on tara.
我們要找目擊證人之間的聯繫
So we're looking for a connection between the witnesses.
吸血鬼主義者心有迷戀 他們不大會去找隨機的受害者
When vampirists become obsessed, they aren't likely to find a random victim.
如果能找到所有受害者之間的交叉點 將能幫上大忙
If we can find a crossrelationship, someone in all the victims' lives, that'll be incredibly helpful.
Gina King認識Tara最久 她們一起上過學
Gina king knew tara the longest. They apparently had some classes together.
我們把她倆的關係全挖出來
Let's get all the information we can on that relationship.
話說 把Tara所有朋友的信息都給我
As a matter of fact, get me everything you can on all of tara's friends.
好吧 明早我會查到他們並跟蹤下去
All right. In the morning i'll track them down and do some followup.
好的
That's fine.
Dante 這位是的Jeff
Dante. This is jeff from "metal life" magazine.
他在寫一篇關於藝術家跨界風格...
He's writing a story on artists who cross over…
"跨界" 我還有"跨界風格"呀 的Jeff?
Cross over. Is that what I do,jeff from "metal life"?
算是呀 你的音樂也不是 純粹的哥特 對吧?
I guess,kind of. You're not totally goth,right?
吸血鬼的這檔子事兒...
That whole vampire thing you do is…
啊 吸血鬼的這檔子事兒?
Ah,the vampire thing?
對 你的表演 對特定的人群很有吸引力
Yeah,your act. It appeals to certain people.
絕望又痛苦的人們 盡力又無力掌控現實 我的音樂對他們最有吸引力
It appeals to desperate, sad people with,at best,a tenuous hold on reality.
我能引用你這句話嗎?
Can I quote you on that?
可以 請自便吧
Sure. Knock yourself out.
別 可別引用那句話 我能把他拉回來 再...
No,don't use that quote. 'Cause I can just get him back, get another…
別操心了 夥計
You know what, don't even bother,man.
他早就過了氣兒了 威士忌在哪?
He was old news 5 years ago. Where's the scotch?
聽著 是這樣的 他最近不在狀態
Listen,here's the thing, he's not on his game lately.
簡直和我在喬治敦大學時 租的第一所公寓一模一樣
This is almost exactly like my first apartment in georgetown.
我媽希望我住在學校 但我鐵了心要自力更生 所以...
My mom wanted me to stay on campus, but I was determined to make it,so...
我週末去當服務員 供著公寓
I waitressed on the weekends to swing it.
那得是多出色的服務員吶 能養得起喬治敦的公寓
You must have been a hell of a waitress to swing an apartment in georgetown.
我差勁死了 能供得起房子 是因為我媽每周都給我打錢
No,i sucked.I only got by 'cause my mom put money in my account every week
然後彼此心照不宣
and we both pretended I didn't know.
看樣子她在學習拍電影
Looks like she was studying to make movies.
Rossi
Rossi.
這傢伙是誰?
Who is this guy?
如今 想瞭解一個年輕女孩的生活
Well,if you want to look into a young girl's life today,
你得進入她的myspace facebook和twitter賬戶
You have to access her myspace, facebook,and twitter accounts.
我給地球上最性感的黑客打電話
I'll call the sexiest hacker on the planet.
他肯定不會把那句話寫進文章堛
I don't think he's going to print that quote.
管他呢?
Who cares?
不該那麼說你的歌迷呀
You shouldn't say stuff like that about your fans.
也許我就該一跳了之 我可是吸血鬼呀
Maybe i'll just jump off. I mean,i'm a vampire.
也許我能隨風飛走
Maybe I could just fly away.
我不喜歡談論這個
I don't like that kind of talk.
怎麼了 Ray 害怕會失去你的搖錢樹?
What's wrong,ray, afraid you're gonna lose your cash cow?
你怎麼了?
What's happened to you?
這沒關係 別這樣 我們曾經很開心的 還記得嗎?
It doesn't matter. Come on. We used to have fun,remember?
我不再寫歌了
I don't make music anymore.
而是製造場面 我只是在演戲
I make events. I play a character.
你賣唱片呀
You sell records.
我的歌又爬不上銷量榜了
It's not as if I exactly light up the sales charts anymore,anyway.
一定還能大賣的
You'll sell again.
Ray 你可能是我僅有的朋友了 但是...
Ray,you may be the only friend I have left, but...
你騙起人來可真蹩腳
You're a pretty crappy liar.
真對不起! 是我的錯 是我不對
I'm so sorry! It's my fault. It's my fault.
讓我幫你吧
Let me help you.
你的手真吸引人
Interesting hand.
你知道我是誰嗎? 知道
Do you know who I am? Yeah.
你是那個唱歌的人 這是你的派對 不是嗎?
I mean, you're the music guy. This is your party,right?
是的 這是…這是我的派對 但是...
Yes. This is… This is for me,but...
我有個兜子 堶掘侉﹞F 能讓咱倆非常高興的東西
I have a pocket full of what will make us both feel so much happier.
是嗎? 咱們一塊兒離開這兒吧
You do? So let's get out of here.
真的嗎? 真的 來吧 咱們走
Really? Yeah. Come on,let's go.
你不會後悔的
You won't be sorry.
唾液還沒有經DNA確認 但是我們會 把它送到實驗室檢測的
The saliva hasn't been dna i.d.'d, but we have it going through the lab.
你們可以把樣本送到當局實驗室 然後催他們快點兒處理
You can have the samples sent over to the local bureau lab and have them rush it.
到明天你至少得有點兒結果
You should have something by sometime tomorrow.
我現在就送過去
I'll have it sent right over.
這些不是咬痕 看這些邊緣 是剃刀一樣鋒利的東西留下的
They're not bites. Look at the edges. They're razor sharp.
如果是牙齒咬的會留下一個 粗糙的撕裂邊緣
A tooth would leave a ragged,torn edge.
桌上有幾張動物咬痕的照片 可以對比一下
I have some photos of animal bites on the table for comparison.
是某種鑽孔工具嗎?
Some sort of boring instrument,then?
非常鋒利而且非常有效
Very sharp and very efficient.
如果不是咬痕 那麼唾液 是死後舔的時候留下的?
Well,if it isn't a bite, then the saliva, is it from licking,afterwards?
也許吧 我從來沒見過像這樣的東西
Maybe. I haven't seen anything like it.
這樣的不明嫌犯一旦開始... 情況就只能越來越糟
Once an unsub like this gets started... It only gets worse.
我是Chase Manning 12號新聞直升機 位於San Fernando 谷101號公路上方
This is chase manning, news chopper 12, over the 101 freeway in the san fernando valley.
在一個出口匝道上又發現了屍體 與前幾天那一樁情形相同
Apparently a second body in as many days has been found near an offramp.
媒體是無孔不入啊
So much for keeping the media out.
Penelope? 能開始了嗎?
Penelope? Are we in yet?
都靠你了
All yours.
我總是很討厭這樣調查 一個人的一生
I always feel skeevy going through someone's life like this.
看起來所有的密碼都被保護了 所以可能無法...
Ok,so everything looks like it's password protected, so you might not even be able to…
你都破解了是不是? 密碼是Cullen
You're in already, aren't you? The password was cullen.
可不是 Colon(直腸)?
Of course. Colon?
是Cullen 堛漣l血鬼家族
Cullen. The vampire family from "twilight."
是啥?
What's "twilight"?
你除了讀技術書籍之外 還讀別的書嗎?
Do you ever read anything other than technical books?
英文的不是很多
Not much in english.
我看看能發現點兒什麼 我的承受力可是很強的
Ok,i'll see what I can dredge. My love is strong.
好的 謝謝
Ok,thanks.
側寫準備的怎麼樣了? 不知道 其實我從沒覺得真正準備好過
How's the profile coming? I don't know. I never really feel ready,you know?
沒事的 我得先跟Tara的bff談談
It'll be fine.I am gonna go talk to tara's bff
免得媒體窮追猛打 事態就無法控制了
before the media requests come in and it gets too crazy.
bff是什麼? 永遠的死黨
What's a bff? Best friend forever.
我要跟你一塊兒去嗎? 不 你要準備側寫
Should I go with you? No. You have a profile to deliver.
真該好好準備側寫了
I should really work on it a little more.
Reid 你拿我手機幹什麼?
Reid. What are you doing with my phone?
Derek  Spence已經準備好側寫了
Derek,hey,um, spence is ready for the profile.
為什麼 是的  他就在我旁邊
Why,yes,he is, right here.
我很快回來
I'll be back.
好的Reid 我們馬上回來
All right,reid. We'll be right in.
Hotch Reid準備好側寫了 好的
Hotch,reid's ready with the profile. Good.
公路巡邏隊天剛亮的時候 發現了屍體
Highway crew found her just as the sun was coming up.
屍體在這埵h久了?
How long's she been here?
體溫還沒有完全冷卻 也許一小時
Barely even cold yet. Hour,maybe.
"你這騙子" 相同的信息
The liar. The same message.
顯然不是單獨針對Tara
Apparently it wasn't taraspecific.
那我就好奇這是什麼意思了
I wonder what it means, then.
第一次連續兩天殺人
The first victim on a consecutive day.
Kim警探 讓現場技術人員隨時 通知我們調查過程嗎?
Detective kim, can you have your crime scene techs keep us apprised of the processing?
我們準備好進行初步的側寫了
We're ready with a preliminary profile.
真快 不明嫌犯也越來越快
That's quick. So's this unsub.
我們要找的 不是超自然意義上的吸血鬼
We aren't looking for a vampire in the supernatural sense,
只是這個不明嫌犯對人血 有著強烈的渴求
Only in the sense that this unsub has a very strong desire, a need,for human blood.
幸運的是 吸血鬼主義者具有顯著特徵 能幫助我們找到他
Now,fortunately, vampirists display several characteristics which will be helpful in finding him.
他會反覆割傷自己
He will have cut himself repeatedly.
這叫做"自動吸血主義" 本質上要成為自己的第一個犧牲者
It's called autovampirism, essentially becoming his own first victim.
他就是通過這種方式第一次吸人血
It's the way by which he first tasted human blood.
大部分的吸血鬼主義者對此感到極度羞愧 因此會穿長袖襯衫
Most vampirists are incredibly ashamed of this and will wear longsleeved shirts
以此來掩蓋這一行為
in order to conceal it.
其次 這種人曾有較長的虐待動物史
Secondly,there will be a long history of animal abuse,
首先是虐待較小的動物 比如昆蟲和齧齒動物
Starting with smaller animals such as insects and rodents
然後演變成虐待大一些的動物 比如說狗和貓
and then working his way up to larger things… Dogs and cats.
儘管這是在其他連環殺手身上發現的 廣泛認可的三個殺人特質之一
Though this is a wellrecognized component of the homicidal triad seen in other serial killers,
在吸血鬼主義者身上 這個特質更為明顯
In the case of the vampirist, it's more pronounced.
很有意思的是 他不會像其他 有變態心理的人那樣
There will, interestingly enough, not be any animal torture,
對動物進行任何折磨
As with other psychopathologies.
殺戮並不是關鍵 它僅僅是獲得血液的一種手段
The killing isn't the point, it's merely a means by which to obtain the blood.
仔細查找你們手中動物管理的相關記錄 盡可能查得久遠一些
Look hard at your animal control sections records, as far back as you can.
這些記錄 很可能有不明嫌犯 青少年時的犯罪記錄
They will probably have some record of this unsub as an adolescent.
如今 這個人很有可能 住在破舊的老房子
This guy also most likely lives in a poorly kept older home.
他需要一幢房子 而不是一間公寓 可以不受干擾
He needs a house for the privacy, not an apartment.
吸乾一個人的血是需要時間的
It takes some time to drain a body completely of blood.
沒人打擾的時間
Uninterrupted time.
不明嫌犯很可能與年長女性同住 祖母 媽媽 甚至是嬸嬸
This unsub also most likely lives with an elderly woman, a grandmother,a mother, even an aunt.
你是怎麼知道的?
How could you know that?
這種精神疾病 通常伴有極度的精神分裂
This type of mental illness, accompanied by extreme schizophrenia,
主宰著一個家庭的存在
Dominates a family's entire existence.
通常家庭因此而破裂 女人成為支撐家庭的主要角色
It often leads to a broken home, and a woman ends up as primary caregiver.
男人通常會離開
The men generally leave.
還有一點 這種精神異常藏不了很久
Oh,and one more thing. This type of disorder cannot be hidden for long.
我可以肯定 有人已經知道 這個不明嫌犯病得異常嚴重
I guarantee you someone out there already knows this unsub is very,very sick.
你沒事吧? 還好吧? 要... 要我叫醫生來嗎?
You ok? You all right? Should i…should I call somebody?
告訴我發生什麼了 跟我說 告訴我
Tell me what's happening. Talk to me. Talk to me.
天啊 我停不下來了
Oh,my god. I can't stop it.
我想要停下來 好的
I want to. Yeah.
但是我停不下來
But I can't stop it.
你得幫我 我知道 我會的
You gotta help me. I know. I will.
你得幫我 我會的 你沒事吧?
You gotta help me. I will. Are you all right?
我不能阻止它 告訴我
I can't stop it. Talk to me.
過來
Come here.
我們會解決這個問題的 好嗎? 我會解決的
We're gonna fix this,ok? I'm gonna fix this.
Morgan探員 我們已經確認了 今早發現的受害人
Agent morgan, we've identified this morning's victim.
Erin Hickman 她昨晚在一個活動的酒會工作
Erin hickman. She worked for a caterer at an event last night.
他們還在那兒清理
They're still there cleaning up.
我在哪堹鄑鋮閵asters女士?
Where can I find ms. Masters?
她就在那兒 謝謝你
She's right there. Thank you.
打攪一下 Masters女士? 我是洛城警局的Kim副隊長
Excuse me. Ms.masters? I'm lieutenant kim,lapd.
是有關Erin的事嗎? 是的女士
Is this about erin? Yes,ma'am.
她真的死了嗎? 是的女士 我很抱歉
Is she really dead? Yes,ma'am. I'm sorry.
這兩位是FBI探員 Morgan和Prentiss FBI?
These are FBI agents morgan and prentiss. Fbi?
Erin Hickman 是你的員工嗎? 昨晚之前都是
Erin hickman work for you? Well,till last night.
派對的中途她就翹班了 翹班?
She walked out on me in the middle of the party. Walked out?
就我所知 她前腳還在後腳就沒影了
All I know is she was here one minute and gone the next.
她經常這麼不負責任嗎?
Was it uncommon for her to be irresponsible?
她都死了 我也不想說壞話 她在毒品方面有點兒問題
Look,i don't want to speak ill of the… she had a problem with drugs.
我看一下
Excuse me.
Morgan 我們在Tara的家 發現了他的海報
Morgan. We saw a poster of him in tara's house.
視頻 請講
Speak to me,vision.
Garcia 給我所有歌手Dante的資料
Garcia,give me everything you've got on a singer named dante.
Dante 那個吸血的傢伙? 我正要給你們電話
Dante,the vampire guy? I was just about to call you.
你認識他?
You know him?
他是所有受害者的唯一共通點
Uh,he's the one thing that all of our victims have in common.
這是什麼意思?
What do you mean?
她們在網絡上給這個傢伙 建了一個神社
They have cyber shrines set up for this guy.
她們崇拜他 她們都被他的音樂迷住了
They worship him. They're obsessed with his music.
他的新專輯今天出爐 名字就叫"你這騙子"
Well,his new album comes out today and it's called "the liar."
"你這騙子" 我知道 這不就是寫在她們身上的詞嗎?
"the liar," I know. And isn't that what was written on them?
所有的受害人 包括之前的兩個 都是他的鐵桿粉絲
Ok,uh,all of our victims, including the first two, were diehard fans.
Tara和Gina … 她是Tara的朋友 幾乎可以說是管理著歌迷俱樂部
Tara and gina… that's tara's friend… they were practically running his fan club.
最後一個受害人Erin Hickman 又是怎麼回事?
What about erin hickman, our latest victim?
Erin Hickman 我還沒有交叉比對這個名字
Erin hickman…i haven't run across that name.
我們得會會這個叫Dante的傢伙
Ok,we need to talk to this dante guy.
Garcia 能查到地址嗎?
Garcia,can you get us an address?
恐怕得查一會兒吧
That's gonna take a little while.
這些明星都躲在層層隱私之下
These celebrities are protected by layers of privacy.
要挖這個信息 可是深得...
It's like finding information on a deeply…
地址是Holmby山 Greenvale環路 22423號
22423 greenvale circle, holmby hills.
正把GPS坐標傳給你們
Gps coordinates are uploading to you now.
對了 他真名叫Paul Davies
And his name is paul davies,by the way.
也查查他的犯罪記錄
Run him for a criminal record,too.
沒問題 謝謝你P.G
You got it. Thanks,p.g.
不敢想像她能在我身上查出什麼
I'd hate to think what she could find out about me.
我寧可想都不想
Oh,i prefer not even to consider it.
這不像有很多破敗的單親家庭住房
It doesn't look like a lot of poorly maintained singlefamily homes.
是不像
No.
我討厭這樣問 但你們的側寫 會不會有時偏差很大?
I hate to ask this, but are your profiles this far off sometimes?
從來沒有過
They haven't been yet.
也許這個人並非我們的不明嫌犯 只是解案的其中一環
This probably isn't our unsub, just a piece of the puzzle.
看來我們是錯了
I could get used to this.
這絕對不是破房子
This is definitely not poorly maintained.
這堥S有一樣東西符合側寫的
One of these things does not belong.
Garcia 能幫我查個車牌嗎?
Hey,garcia,can you run a plate for me?
這不是我們要找的傢伙吧? 我非常懷疑
This isn't our guy,is it? I highly doubt it.
諸位有何貴幹? 你是Dante嗎?
May I help you guys? Dante?
不是 你不是那個歌手嗎?
No. You're not the singer?
Dante不是我的名字 他是我扮演的 一個角色  那你們是誰?
Dante's not my name. He's a character I play. So who are you guys?
我們是來調查一項謀殺… 先生!
We're investigating a murder… Sir!
你介意跟我們回去回答幾個問題嗎?
Would you mind coming in to answer a few questions?
Prentiss你在做什麼?
Prentiss, what are you doing?
這輛車是Erin Hickman的 那個受害人的車
That car is erin hickman's car. The victim's car.
先生你介意跟我們走一趟嗎?
Would you mind coming in,sir?
我是Elizabeth Chambers 正在洛城警局外繼續關注事態發展
This is elizabeth chambers outside the los angeles police department with a story we're still developing.
唱作人Dante 因涉嫌近期在洛城地區
The singersongwriter known as dante has been taken into custody by the FBI
犯下一系列命案 已被FBI收審
As a suspect in a recent string of murders in the los angeles area.
多長時間了 有三十分鐘嗎?
What's it been,30 minutes?
你的音樂事業怎麼辦?
What about your music?
歡迎來到世界媒體之都
Welcome to the media capital of the world.
天啊
Oh,god.
怎麼這麼快來了? 天曉得 他們總是這樣
How the hell did they get here so fast? Who knows? They always do.
聽著 我們強行穿過去
Now listen up. We're gonna have to push through.
你們能不能至少給我披個 夾克什麼的?
Can you at least put a jacket over me or something?
要衝出去的話 現在就得沖
If we're gonna go we gotta go now.
退後! 所有人退後! 退後!
Back off! Everyone back off! Back off!
麻煩退後! 退後! 退後!
Back up,please! Back up! Back up!
我是FBI的! 麻煩大家到這邊來 我有官方聲明
I'm with the fbi! I have an official statement if you'll just come over here,please.
他沒事吧? 他帶著槍了 別停下
Is he gonna be ok? He's got a gun. Keep moving.
就在這兒 非常感謝
Right in here. Thank you very much.
好的 現在這只是初步調查
Ok,this is just a preliminary investigation right now.
這事太不對勁兒了
A lot of this doesn't add up.
我們以前也犯過錯 從來沒錯這麼多
We've been wrong before. Not this much.
情況複雜了
The plot thickens.
十年前他因為家庭暴力被捕過
He was arrested for domestic violence 10 years ago.
有多嚴重?
How bad.
Garcia本來能找到備案的 可是案底都給清了 誰知道呢?
Well,garcia was able to find the battery charge, but it was expunged, so who knows?
歡迎見識名人司法世界
Again,welcome to celebrity justice.
他似乎很生氣 我很好奇原因
He's pretty agitated. I wonder why.
這兒的名人都不太習慣關號子
Celebrities out here aren't used to being put in the box.
可好像不止是不習慣的問題
This seems more than that,though.
那我不知道了 大家都對這幫人言聽計從的
I don't know. These are people everyone falls down around,defers to.
他們習慣別人說好話
Adulation is their norm.
Prentiss 你去審他也許不錯 我?
You know,prentiss, that may be a good way for you to play him. Me?
你是指證他的人 他也許把你看成是敵人
You were the one who pointed at him. He may see you as an adversary.
讓他放下戒心
Have him offguard.
你怎麼和那幫記者說的?
So,what did you tell the press?
我鄭重聲明了我討厭洛杉磯 這兒怎麼樣?
My official statement was that I hate los angeles. What's happening?
Prentiss打頭陣 好辦法
Prentiss is gonna take the lead. Good choice.
記住 如果他是不明嫌犯 他會對自己的 精神紊亂感到羞愧 利用這一點
Remember, if he is the unsub, he's ashamed of the disorder, so use that to your advantage.
跟他說 你不能相信他會做出這種事
Tell him you can't believe that someone like him could do this.
扔給他一根救命繩 好
Throw him a lifeline. Right.
問他要簽名
Ask him for his autograph.
對 對啊 拍他馬屁
Right. Right. Adulation.
Davies先生 請坐 別緊張
Mr. Davies. Have a seat,relax.
別緊張? 我怎麼能他媽的不緊張?
Relax? How the hell am I supposed to relax?
請坐下
Please sit.
我一直打電話給我的經紀人 但沒有信號
I've been trying to call my manager, but I can't get a signal.
審訊室一般都沒有網絡
These interrogation rooms don't usually have cell service.
那我能用什麼別的電話嗎?
Is there another phone that I can use?
我… 我覺得一定是什麼地方搞錯了
I…i think there's been a really big mistake.
沒有什麼搞錯的地方
There's been no mistake.
我相信你和這些命案沒什麼瓜葛
I'm sure that you couldn't have had anything to do with what's happened.
是嗎? 可是你帶我來這兒的啊
Really? I mean,you're the one that brought me in here.
警方給我的有些信息並不準確
The police gave me some bad information.
你不是警察? 好 把他搞糊塗了 精神分裂病人分不清
You're not the police? Good,she's confusing him. Schizophrenics can't follow that.
我們倆都不應該待在警局的審訊室
Neither one of us is the type of person who belongs in a police interrogation room.
我是FBI的特別督察探員Emily Prentiss
Supervisory special agent emily prentiss, federal bureau of investigation.
FBI的?
Fbi?
當然了 你是誰我知道
And,of course, I know who you are.
你是我的偶像
I'm a big fan.
真的? 你很驚訝嗎?
Really? Does that surprise you?
對 是的 我很驚訝
Yeah. Yeah,that's a surprise.
好吧 在正式開始前...
Ok. Well, before we get started...
你不介意吧?
Would you mind?
介意什麼?
Would I mind what?
要我開口真挺難為情的 不過機會難得
Well,i hate to ask, but I don't usually get opportunities like this.
這他媽的算什麼? 你根本不是我的粉
What the hell is this? You're no fan of mine.
你們以為我是笨蛋嗎?
You people think I'm stupid.
這樣的自相矛盾應該會讓精神分裂的人 完全分不清東西南北的
That kind of contradiction should completely confuse a schizophrenic.
這說不通啊
They can't make sense of it.
我是不是涉嫌什麼了?
Am I suspected of something?
你新專輯的名字叫什麼 今天發的那張?
Wh'she name they canof your new album,t. The one that comes out today?
她是不是 死了? 是的
Is she… Dead? Yes.
手上寫著你新專輯的名字
With the name of your new album written on her.
這個詞組很常見 是嗎? 在我看來可奇怪啊
It's a common phrase. Is it? It seems a little odd to me.
是特製 不是泛指
The instead of a.
這個女孩呢 昨晚還跟你回家了
And this girl went home with you last night.
她也死了?
She's dead?
你能解釋一下嗎?
Can you explain that?
我... 我不... 我不記得了
I…i don't… I don't remember.
你不記得傷害她了? 不 不記得
You don't remember hurting her? No. No.
她們的血都流乾了
Their blood was drained.
是喉嚨上的小孔堿y出來的 什麼?
From holes in their throats. What?
你是吸血鬼嗎 Davies先生?
Are you a vampire, mr. Davies?
你這是開玩笑吧
You can't be serious.
那只是我扮演的角色 舞台角色
It's a character I play, a stage act.
有時候事情會失去控制的
You know,sometimes things get out of hand.
不 不會的 這也... 太瘋狂了
No,no. This is…this is crazy.
我不知道那女孩怎麼會成那樣的
I don't know how that girl ended up like that.
我要叫我的經紀人過來
I think I need my manager here.
你得自己回答問題 好孩子
You're gonna do this all on your own, just like a big boy.
可我有權請律師
But I have the right to a lawyer.
你要叫律師嗎? 不
Are you asking for an attorney? No.
我請求與我經紀人聯繫 讓他去請律師
I'm asking to speak to my manager so he can find one.
我要電話 我要打電話 我得打電話
I need a phone. I need to make a call. I need to make a call.
律師沒來 他不願說你也沒辦法 Prentiss
There's nothing you can do when they lawyer up,prentiss.
Reid博士 Spence 怎麼樣了?
Dr. Reid here. Spence,what's going on?
嫌犯是個什麼搖滾歌星
The possible suspect's some sort of rock and roll star.
不是吧? 真的 但很多東西都不符合我們的側寫
Seriously? Yeah. A lot of it doesn't fit the profile,though.
我能幫上什麼忙嗎? 媒體倒是特別關注
Anything I can do? There's a lot of media attention.
好的 我已經到Gina家了
All right.Well, I'm already here at gina's house,
我先搜集點資料 一會就回去 太好了 謝謝你
so let me get some info and i'll be back. Great. Thank you so much.
這些表現都說不通啊 對
None of this makes any sense. No.
電視上說他的新專輯都賣翻天了
Television is saying his new record is selling through the roof.
所有周邊商品都是
All of his stuff is.
就在他被懷疑是連環殺人犯的消息 公佈以後
As soon as his being questioned in an actual string of murders became public.
那句話怎麼說來著? 能露臉就是好宣傳
What do they say? Any publicity's good publicity.
我們該拿他怎麼辦呢?
What are we gonna do with him?
Hotchner
Hotchner.
既然他要聯繫經紀人
Well,he wants to talk to his manager,
那我們也許可以讓他聯繫 看看對方知道些什麼
so maybe we let him make that call and find out what that guy knows.
值得一試
It's worth a try.
你確定? 好的 謝謝 有事?
You sure? Ok,thanks. Something?
實驗室打來的 受害人喉嚨上的 唾液樣本 DNA顯示是女性的
That's the lab. The saliva samples from the victims' throats… the dna's from a woman.
別敲了 別敲了 奶奶在睡覺 她會被吵醒的
Stop. Don't to that. Grandma's asleep. She's gonna wake up.
所以你別敲了 我要回後院去了
So you have to stop it. I need to go to the yard.
Gina
Gina.
Gina Gina 我是FBI的
Gina. Gina. I'm with the… fbi.
女性的? 這極其罕見了 但不是不可能
A woman? That's incredibly rare. But not impossible.
是 但Renfield癥發展到如此程度 一般不會這樣的
No,but renfield's with this type of aggression… it almost never presents this way.
我們就覺得什麼地方不對了 我們的側寫從來沒這麼離譜 Reid
Ok,we knew something was wrong. Our profiles have never been this far off,reid.
再看看資料 朝女性的方向找 看我們有什麼地方遺漏了
Go back and work it with a woman. See if there's anything we may have missed.
是你要打電話給你的經紀人
You wanted to call your manager.
我能有點隱私嗎? 沒這規矩
Can I have some privacy? That's not how it works.
Ray 老天啊 夥計 專輯賣得可火了
Ray. Holy hell,man,the record's gone through the roof.
你說什麼? 你的專輯都賣空了
What do you mean? Yeah,it's flying off the shelves.
我跟你說過我會搞定的 跟你說好的 一切都會好的
I told you I'd fix it. I told you. Yeah,everything's good.
你馬上就能飆回排行榜 一切都會和以前一樣的
You're gonna be back on top, everything's gonna go right back to normal,
你也不用再吸毒了
you can stop doing the drugs.
Ray 我現在和FBI的人在警局
Ray,i'm at the police station with the fbi.
我知道 我知道 我知道 不用擔心
I know,i know,i know. Don't worry about it.
不用擔心? 對 不用 不用擔心
Don't worry? No,don't…don't worry about it.
聽著 沒什麼證據能定你的罪 什麼都沒有
Look,there's nothing that could be tied to you, absolutely nothing.
會沒事的 夥計
It's all good,man.
起來 我們走 走
Come on,let's go. Yes.
你幹了什麼了 Ray?
What did you do,ray?
這事你知道的越少越好
The less you know about it the better.
看 我得去辦妥這事 然後我馬上就回來
Look,i gotta take care of this thing, and then i'll be right back.
我會過去的 讓我先把事情解決了
I'll be down there. Let me just fix this.
Ray... 嘿 放輕鬆 好嗎?
Ray… hey,relax,would ya?
一切都會沒事的
It's gonna be all right.
他做了什麼嗎?
Did he do something?
我不知道
I don't know.
他說什麼?
What did he say?
他說他要去把事情解決了
He said he'd be down to fix it.
解決什麼事?
Fix what?
我想是解決這件事情吧
Fix this,i suppose.
但 他沒問過你"這"是什麼事?
But he didn't ask you what "this" was.
沒
No.
Gina
Gina.
Gina 我叫Jennifer Jareau
Gina. My name is jennifer jareau.
Gina你跑哪去了?
Gina,where'd you go?
Gina...
這他媽的是誰?
Who the hell is that?
你到底接到了啥樣的 粉絲留言呢 吸血鬼先生?
What kind of fan mail do you get,mr. Vampire?
女人... 什麼會變? 什麼不會變?
A woman…what changes, what doesn't?
年長女性...
Older female...
哦 不
Oh,no.
是我 Reid 我找了粉絲到給Dante的留言
Yeah. Uh,reid, uh,i found fan mail to dante.
吸血鬼粉絲留言 超瘋狂 著魔了?
Vampire fan mail. It's bananas. Obsessional?
有過之而無不及 Tara的朋友Gina
Ad infinitum and beyond.Tara's friend gina…
她寫的那些東西... 他就是她的上帝
the stuff she writes… she…he's her god.
吸血鬼上帝  她為他而活 她說 她甚至不惜為他殺人
A vampire god. She lives for him. She said she'll kill for him.
而她符合每一項側寫 夥計們!
And she fits every other piece of the profile. Guys!
Tara生前在一起的那個女孩 Gina 就是她
The girl tara was with before she died… gina…it's her.
你有地址嗎? 有 我想JJ現在已經在那了
Do you have an address? Yeah. I think jj is there right now.
我們走
Let's go.
這他媽的是誰?
Who the hell is she?
我太沮喪了 所有事情 都被搞砸了太糟了
I'm so upset. It's all going to go bad.
別這麼想了 你必須...必須殺了她
Forget that. You've got… you've got to kill her.
一切都搞砸了
It's all going bad.
聽我說 我們必須幫助Dante 你必須再幫Dante一次
Listen to me, we've got to help dante. You gotta help dante again.
Dante? 沒錯
Dante? Yeah.
他...他...他會生氣的
He's…he's… he's gonna be angry.
不 不不不 我保證 你不殺了這女人 他才會生氣呢
No,no,no,no. I promise. He'll only be angry if you don't kill this woman.
聽著 你得再多殺一個女孩 才能加入他 成為不死族 明白?
Listen, you gotta hurt one more girl and then you'll be able to join him in the undead. Ok?
她一直沒接 繼續打
She isn't answering. Keep trying.
你只要再多殺一個 Dante就能活了 就一個?
You just have to do one more and dante will be able to live then. Just one?
就再殺這一個女孩 然後你就可以 跟我們說好的那樣 加入不死族了
Just this one more girl and then you can join the undead, just like we promised.
你說過Tara是最後一個了 你是這麼說的 你說過的
You said that tara was the last one. That's what you said. You said.
現在又冒出來一個... 這是最後一個了
Now it's the other girl… this is the last one.
這是最後一個了 然後你就能加入Dante 成為不死族
The last one that you have to do, and then you can join dante and be the undead.
就像我們說過的那樣 記得嗎? 記得嗎?
Just like we talked about, remember? Remember?
就一個... 就再一個
Just one... Just one more.
然後是你自己 就像他承諾的那樣
And then yourself. Just like he promised.
就一個...好吧 就一個
Just one... Ok. Just one.
最後一個 最後一個 拿著 來 拿著
Last one. Last one. Take it. Go on,take it.
非常好
Beautiful.
她到哪...
Where did she…
不准動
don't move.
JJ? JJ!
Jj? Jj!
在後面!
In the back!
我的 這是我的 是我的 不能...不能給你
Mine. This is mine. It's mine. You can't… you can't have it.
走開 走開
Go away. Go away.
JJ
Jj.
舉起手來! 把手放在我能看見的地方!
Show me your hands! Let me see your hands!
沒事 沒事 把手舉起來!
It's ok. It's ok. Get your hands clear!
不不 求你了 你得...不不不!
No,no,please,you have to… no,no,no,no! No,no,no!
那血會變質的! 求你們! 別這樣!
The blood is going bad! Please! Please don't do this!
你帶武器了嗎? 沒沒沒
Are you armed? No,no,no. No. Go,go!
嘿 我和這事一點關係也沒有 這不是我幹的
Hey,i got nothing to do with this. Hey,it's not me.
是那妞干的 這和我一點關係也沒有
It's the chick. It's got nothing to do with me.
發生什麼事了嗎?
Has something happened?
是你的經紀人
It was your manager.
他利用了你的一個粉絲
He used a fan of yours.
什麼? 一個年輕女孩
What? A young girl.
她一直給你寫信 說她想殺人吸血
She'd been writing you letters about wanting to kill someone for their blood.
我從來...從來沒收到過
I never…i never received anything.
沒錯 他收了
No,he did.
而我想他大概是覺得 可以利用此事進行宣傳
And I guess he thought he could use it for publicity.
他是對的 你的新專輯賣得非常好
He was right. Your new album is selling very well.
我從來沒要求過這些
I never asked for that. Well...
他在哪? 你的經紀人? 他被拘留了
Where is he? Your manager? He's in custody.
他還好嗎? 我能為他做點什麼嗎?
Is he ok? Is there anything I can do for him?
他會需要個好律師
He's gonna need a good lawyer.
那女孩會怎麼樣?
What about the girl?
不知道她最後會怎麼樣 她已經非常不正常了
I don't know where she'll end up. She's pretty sick.
如果可以的話 我也希望能幫幫她
I'd like to help her, too,if I can.
這就結束了? 我現在可以走了?
That's all? I can go now?
這就結束了
That's all.
你知道嗎 我真正想做的 就只有做音樂而已
You know,all I really ever wanted to do was make music.
但我不清楚究竟何時起 我覺得這不夠了
And I'm not sure when that stopped being enough.
嘿 你們覺得Davies會繼續 以Dante的身份演出嗎?
Hey,do you guys think davies will continues to perform as dante?
那個角色應該對四名女性的被害 負有責任
The character's probably responsible for the murder of 4 women.
要是他還有一點良知 Dante會隨她們而逝
If he has any conscience at all, dante died with them.
謝謝 你還好嗎?
Thanks. Are you ok?
沒事 醫生說會疼一陣子 但我沒事 真的
Yeah. Doctor said it'll be sore for a while, but I'm fine,really.
沒跟你一起去見Gina 我覺得太過意不去了
I feel so bad I didn't go with you to interview gina.
Spence打住好嗎? 我們根本不可能 預知她會是個危險人物
Spence,stop, all right? We had no way of knowing she was gonna be dangerous.
她只不過是受害人的朋友罷了
She was just the friend of a victim.
好吧我承認 是個精神分裂的朋友 外加一個反社會的搭檔
Granted,a schizophrenic friend with a sociopathic partner.
還有把鐵鍬
And a shovel.
說真的Reid 我們根本沒辦法預知 Gina內心會蘊藏著那樣的憤怒
Seriously,reid, we had no way of knowing that gina had that type of anger inside of her.
是啊 但是她對Dante著了魔
Yeah,but she was obsessed with dante.
我應該想到 那種程度的迷戀 會導致被人操控
I should have known that that level of fixation can lead to manipulation.
只有迷戀和精神分裂結合時才會出現 這我們根本無法預知
But only when the fixation's coupled with schizophrenia, which we had no way of knowing.
迷戀能邪惡到如此程度 還是讓我汗毛直豎啊
Still it never ceases to amaze me how dark obsession can get.
就為一個流行歌星?
And with a pop star?
我對"鼠幫"可著魔了 可絕不願意為Frank或Dean殺人啊
I mean,i was obsessed with the rat pack, but I wouldn't have killed for frank or dean.
五六十年代爵士演唱組 兩人是其中成員
不 你只會喝威士忌抽雪茄
No,you just drank whiskey and smoked cigars.
這話竟然出自 最愛專輯是 披頭士的人之口
This from the man who's favorite record is the beatles' white album.
就算曼森(連環殺手)劫機 也別因此毀了大家對專輯的熱愛嘛
Just because manson hijacked it doesn't have to ruin it for the rest of us.
曼森指出該專輯中"Helter Skelter"的歌詞 應驗了自己的某一預言
這就是為什麼我一直鍾愛貝多芬
That's why I stick to beethoven.
曼森的女兒後曾試圖劫機殺死乘客 逼迫釋放曼森
絕對沒機會和犯罪扯上關係
There's no chance of guilt by association.
是啊
Well,yeah.
有部電影叫"發條橙"你看過嗎?
Have you ever seen a movie called "a clockwork orange"?
作家Cyril Connolly曾說過
Writer cyril connolly said,
"為自己寫作無人問津
"better to write for yourself and have no public
好過為人寫作失去自我"
than to write for the public and have no self."
犯罪心理 第五季 第7集
== 結束==
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode07 The Performer